In the late Northern Song Dynasty,
the government was corrupt,
wars raged on for years,
and the people lived in destitution.
Righteous martial artists from all over
snuck into Dongjing,
attempting to approach the Emperor
to change the situation.
Officers of Bingjingwu.
Open the door immediately!
Where is the Director?
In the ice cellar.
My Lord.
Bodies of strangers were found outside the city.
They were all killed by highly skilled martial artists.
The horses ridden by the victims
were all top-grade steeds.
I originally thought
it was a revenge killing.
On one of them,
I found a silk letter.
This silk letter...
It is written in cipher.
The contents of the silk script are still unknown.
I will have someone decode it as soon as possible.
No need.
I will find someone to decode it tomorrow.
What about the hoofbeats just now?
It was an emergency.
I rode the dead man's horse
to hurry back here.
Send these horses to the mule market tomorrow
and sell them.
Let's see who comes to buy this horse.
The shopkeeper said today,
whoever brings in customers
gets double the reward.
Is it true?
Let's go.
Come in and take a look.
It won't cost you much.
Come to our shop to rest and have a drink.
Come on, sir.
No, thanks.
To make a living as a loafer,
you don't need to be all things to all men.
Spend a little money.
Hanging out at the theater
and reading storybooks
can bring great benefits.
Look at that guy over there.
He looks strong,
but his steps are getting unsteady.
I'm afraid he is sick.
I presume he has already exhausted his wealth recently.
Look at that one.
He is wearing fine silk clothes,
but there isn't a single piece of jade or precious jewelry on him.
Just a gambler.
They might be regretting
their misplaced bet.
Look at that one.
I am known as the geographic genius of Dongjing,
Meng Qian, the second brother Meng.
Can you be more familiar with
these four rivers and thirty-two bridges than me?
Guest,
is this your first time in Dongjing?
Yes.
Let me show you the way.
Okay.
Meng Xiao Er.
Thank you.
You two.
First time in Dongjing?
Daoist Master.
This young man
is the most famous idler in Bianjing City.
I
read my fortune before going out today.
It said I
would meet noble people.
And here I met you two as soon as I came out.
You two must be
my noble people.
We are newcomers.
We are unfamiliar with this place.
Could you show us around?
Sure.
Oh, show you around?
Walking around.
Okay.
Leave it to me.
Situ Zhen looked for that idler to lead the way.
The war in the south is critical.
Situ Zhen is not on the frontline,
but comes to Bianjing instead.
What is his intention?
Keep an eye on him.
Excuse me.
Let me see.
Selling horses.
Good horses.
Twenty taels each.
Sir,
take a look at the top-grade horses.
Untie me.
All right.
This silk text has been secretly arranged.
A rough glance
shows it mentions the Shangyuan Festival.
Please wait a moment, sister.
Sister-in-law.
You are back.
Why are you earlier than usual?
I made a huge profit today.
Now we have money for Xiaolian's medicine.
You are back.
Are you feeling better today?
Getting better every day.
Sister-in-law.
Xiaolian wants to get out of bed and eat at the table.
No.
The spring cold has just arrived.
She is very weak.
All right.
You watch the stove.
I'll go in and help Xiaolian get dressed.
Sister-in-law,
is this cooked?
Haven't you finished dressing?
Sister-in-law.
Xiaolian.
Brother Meng,
calm down.
What are you doing?
Brother Li Lang's knockout drops
just make them sleep more soundly.
You wouldn't want them to see you like this, would you?
Knockout drops?
My little sister is already physically weak.
You...
Let go of my sister.
Come at me if you have a problem.
After taking that pill,
even if there is only one breath left,
a person can be saved.
Although this medicine is highly effective,
you must take one pill a day
for several months
to see miraculous results.
Otherwise...
Otherwise what?
Missing a single day
will ruin everything,
and even gods cannot save you.
You...
Making things so difficult for a junior like me,
why?
Mr. Meng,
you're no ordinary junior.
Your ancestors served in the Ministry of War,
specializing in mapping.
By your generation,
your family fortune declined.
But you have profound family knowledge.
You grew up
in Dongjing.
You're known as
the Dongjing Geography Ghost.
We came here
to ask you
to continue being our guide.
This is the deposit.
When it's done,
you'll get more than ten times this.
I need to be alive to spend it.
We have long admired the prosperity of Dongjing.
I hope Meng
can, on Shangyuan Night,
help us brothers
ascend the West Tower of Fanlou
to see Dongjing City lit up by lanterns.
Fanlou.
Sister.
Assassination.
Shangyuan Night.
The Emperor.